It's not the size of the dog in the fight, It's
the size of the fight in the dog.
Rudy is a drama, history film directed by David Anspaugh.
Rudy grew up in a steel mill town where most people ended up working,
but wanted to play football at Notre Dame instead.
There were only a couple of problems.
His grades were a little low, his athletic skills were poor, and
he was only half the size of the other players.
But he had the drive and the spirit of 5 people and has
set his sights upon joining the team.
Daniel E. 'Rudy' Ruettiger, played by Sean Astin.
D-Bob, played by Jon Favreau.
Daniel Ruettiger, played by Ned Beatty.
Sherry, played by Lili Taylor.
Fortune, played by Charles S. Dutton.
Jamie O'Hara, played by Vince Vaughn.
Rudy is a 1993 American biographical sports film directed by David Anspaugh.
It is an account of the life of Daniel "Rudy" Ruettiger, who harbored dreams of playing
football at the University of Notre Dame despite significant obstacles.
It was the first film that the Notre Dame administration allowed to be
shot on campus since Knute Rockne, All American in 1940.
In 2005, Rudy was named one of the best 25 sports movies of the previous 25 years in two
polls by ESPN (#24 by a panel of sports experts, and #4 by ESPN.com users).
It was ranked the 54th-most inspiring film of all time in the
American Film Institute's "100 Years" series.
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 18, 1993, and
was released in the United States on October 13, 1993, by TriStar Pictures.
It stars Sean Astin as the title character, along with Ned Beatty,
Jason Miller, Robert Prosky, Lili Taylor and Charles S.
Jon Favreau and Vince Vaughn had supporting roles in their
first appearances in a major studio production.
The script was written by Angelo Pizzo, who created Hoosiers
(1986), which was also directed by Anspaugh.
The film explores themes of underdog, sports, american
football, biography, based on true story.
The tone is emotional.